Guide to the Philippe Halsman Photographs of Yale Affiliated Individuals
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Philippe Halsman photographs of Yale affiliated individuals
1946-1967
RU 911
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The material consists of formal portrait photographs of Yale affiliated individuals, including William F. Buckley, Jr., Henry Ford II, Henry R. Luce and Paul Tillich.
Halsman, Philippe, 1906-1979
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 48-A (YRG 48-A), Yale pictorial records and collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The material was a gift of Jane Halsman Bello and Steve Bello, 2002.
Arrangement
Arranged by topic.
Biographical / Historical
Philippe Halsman was born in Riga, Latvia in 1901. He opened a photography studio in Paris in 1931. He left occupied France for the United States in 1940. Halsman was a founding member and first president of the American Society of Media Photographers, Inc. in 1945. Halsman is best known for his portraits of famous individuals, such as Salador Dali, Albert Einstein and Winston Churchill. His 30 year affiliation with Life magazine resulted in 101 covers. His photographs have been published in numerous books and magazines. Two of his photographs were made into postage stamps. Halsman died in 1979.
Scope and Contents
The material consists of formal portrit photographs of Yale affiliated individuals, including William F. Buckley, Jr., Henry Ford II, Henry R. Luce and Paul Tillich.
Photographs; Bazelon, David T., 1923- -- Portraits; Buckley, William F., Jr., 1925-2008 -- Portraits; Davenport, Russell W. (Russell Wheeler), 1899-1954 -- Portraits; Feiffer, Jules -- Portraits; Ford, Henry, II, 1917-1987 -- Portraits; Halsman, Philippe, 1906-1979; Ingersoll, Ralph, 1900-1985 -- Portraits; Jessup, John Knox, 1907- -- Portraits; Kefauver, Estes, 1903-1963 -- Portraits; Lindsay, John V. (John Vliet), 1921-2000 -- Portraits; Lord, Walter, 1917-2002 -- Portraits; Luce, Henry Robinson, 1898-1967 -- Portraits; Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1892-1971 -- Portraits; Stewart, Potter -- Portraits; Stone, Edward Durell -- Portraits; Symington, Stuart, 1901-1988 -- Portraits; Tillich, Paul, 1886-1965 -- Portraits; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae
- Photographs, 1946-1967; Series I
  - Bazelon, David T., 1959 (Box 1)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr., 1967 (Box 1)
  - Davenport, Russell, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Feiffer, Jules, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Ford, Henry, II, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Ingersoll, Ralph, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Jessup, John Knox, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Kefauver, Estes, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Lindsay, John V., 1965 (Box 1)
  - Lord, Walter, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Luce, Henry R., 1948 (Box 1)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Stewart, Potter, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Stone, Edward Durell, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Symington, Stuart, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Tillich, Paul, 1958 (Box 1)